JEUEL VIVEROS

Dallas, TX 75218

Phone: 214 783-7757 | Email: vjeuel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vjeuel | Github: https://github.com/vjeuel |

Portfolio: https://grafk.design/

SUMMARY

Owning a restaurant for over 16 years, acquired experience in public relations, finances, advertising, and training. While running a restaurant also freelanced as a Graphic Designer, designing advertising materials for various businesses, in 2014 started diving on Digital Design and learned HTML and CSS. Known as a creative, also adaptable, disciplined, organized and loves a challenge, excited to keep learning and looking forward to solving problems. Also fluent in Spanish and Portuguese. Full Stack web developer with focus on Front-End.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

Applications: jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Heroku, Git, Handlebars.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Bootstrap Framework,

Materialize Framework, Material UI Framework, React, MERN Stack.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: 09/2020, GPA 4.0 | Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX. A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js & React, MERN Stack.

TeamTreeHouse: CSS, HTML, Media Queries - 2014

Logo Design, Responsive Web Design - 2017 Flexbox and Grid, Typography, Bootstrap - 2020

College Education: Business Administration | UFMS, Campo Grande, MS, Brazil.

Marketing and Advertising | UCDB, Campo Grande, MS, Brazil.

PROJECTS

CHIEF System | https://github.com/rgarza28/Inventory-Manager | https://lit-meadow-59526.herokuapp.com

- Inventory Management System, to help businesses to have a broad view of inventory at all times and alerts when a certain item is low in stock, decreasing the time of orders fulfillment by 50%.
- Teamed with 3 other students to write and develop this Inventory Management System.
- Led the execution of the Front End Development, User Interface, and User Experience Designs.
- Mobile responsive, developed with React, and used Material UI Framework, plus specific CSS3 styling.

Restaurant User Interface | https://github.com/vjeuel/Digital-Menu-Project | https://tinyurl.com/y6rpjktz

- Full-stack application, created to help restaurants to have a menu presence online, where menu items can be added, changed or deleted.
- Teamed with 3 other students and was responsible for the front-end and wrote most of the back-end of the application.
- Technologies used were Handlebars, JavaScript, jQuery, Express, Signup and Login ability and MySql for databases.
- Mobile responsive using Shoelace Framework and CSS3 for styling.

Hungry at Home | https://github.com/vjeuel/food_api_app | https://vjeuel.github.io/food_api_app/

- For people who are at home in a Covid-19 lockdown, to give access to meals and drinks recipes and also to stay connected with news related to the virus.
- Partnered with 2 other students to work from the ground up on the development of this website.
- Created the design, using CSS3's Media Query in conjunction with the Materialize framework, and also facilitated the API's connections.
- Mobile responsive, written with HTML5, CSS3, Materialize Framework, CSS, and JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer | Freelancer | Dallas, TX | 02/2000 to Present

- Proficient in Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Affinity Designer, Affinity Photo and Affinity Publisher,
 Zoom Video Conferencing
- Restaurant Websites
 - o 2 Restaurant's static websites designed to present menus, specials, and contact information.
 - o Connected both sites to online ordering third party service and had a sales boost of 25% and 32% in revenue respectively.
 - o https://github.com/vjeuel/tonys-pizza | https://tinyurl.com/ychxobt3
 - o https://github.com/vjeuel/carmines-pizzeria-grid | https://tinyurl.com/y9r7hthm

Operation Sales Analyst | South Bend Specialty Pharmacy | South Bend, IN | 09/2019 to Present

- Sales and services researcher
- Google sheets management
- ???

Tony's Pizza and Pasta | Owner-Operator | Dallas, TX | 05/2003 to 06/2019

- Oversaw all the financial aspects of the business, productivity tracking, inventory monitoring, sales forecasting, cash flow projection, payroll, payment of services and suppliers, and taxes.
- Responsible for interviewing, hiring and managing employees.
- Managed the marketing and creative side.
- Had a close relationship with customers on a daily basis.